[Music]
[Laughter]
everyone welcome back to my channel so
today i'll be sharing a short video on
what to look out for when you are buying
insurance so do not buy insurance before
watching this video okay let's go
okay so today i'll be sharing about
things that not every financial
consultant will share with you okay so
uh other than price that most people
look at there are really actually many
other things to look out for okay so
let's get on to it
okay uh first thing we you should do is
to check what you already have and why
should you check because uh you should
be adequately insured and not over or
under insurer so let's say you have some
policies that you don't know about so
you might you might uh you might buy
whatever
that is sufficient to cover the amount
but you actually have some policies that
already cover it so in that case you'll
be over insured and then under insurance
is not a good thing because uh when you
need the money you won't have enough to
uh support yourself like then okay so
all policies are still valid and should
be taken into consideration during
planning so some examples are policies
bought by parents and then
in future you have to take over the
policy uh servicing and i mean the
policy premiums and uh not all policies
are terminate automatically if the
premiums are not paid so
uh for example your parents bought
policies for you like many years ago
then they thought the policy is gone
already but actually it can still be
there
even though the premiums are not paid so
you need to check on all this
okay and then uh if you want to retain
these policies or you will normally need
to make up the premiums not paid in the
last few years and then uh these
premiums that you pay right should be
taken into account for premium
affordability planning
yeah okay so uh how how do you check
what you already have this is the
question how because like most people
only have like paper
everything in paper last time right but
now everything is online really okay
even your super super old policies they
are all online as long as you create
account you can go in and take a look
okay so uh if you are from your policies
are from aia
ge prudential fwd ntc income or tokyo
marine they have this sync pass login so
basically you just go there scan the
sync pass qr code and you're able to log
in really okay some other insurers not
so high tech with sync pass log in will
be a axa
manualized thing like aviva so basically
these are the ones that you really need
to create an account to log in and see
okay
then how to check if it's actually uh
other things like government policy so
even some like government policies right
it's actually with the uh
insurers are with the private insurers
such as a great eastern dependent
protection scheme
or like uh aviva min dev mha insurance
lab so
this view you will need to
log into the individual private insurers
to check because uh
you won't be able to check from the
government website however there are
some policies that the government is the
one that is the issuer so if they are
the issuer you can check from uh
most ide you will be deducted from your
cpf so you can check from your cpf
dashboard so some examples of
governmental policies are like
cashew life home protection scheme
cpf life integrated health shield plan
or medishield life okay so integrated
houston plan is uh normally with the
individual insurers but you can see who
is the individual insurer that you have
your integrated shield plan from if you
want to check from cpa website okay
so uh they will also tell you cover
underneath your life like your pr or
singaporean
yeah
okay let's move on to the second uh
point
so second point is uh you and your
family's health so how can this actually
affect so if it's a heritage thing like
breast cancer huntington disease all
these it can actually affect
whether you are offered on the standard
term standard terms means uh everybody
else playing hundred maybe
uh you also are paying hundreds so
that's standard terms but if you are
paying more it means you are not offered
on standard terms okay
other things is very most importantly is
your health law whether you have
previous instances of like alarms high
glucose level high blood pressure high
lipid levels all this
it can affect insurability so what's
insert insurability is uh
your ability to get full insurance with
no uh exclusions
so like there are many plans around like
for example health shield if you get
exclusion can be exclusion of your leg
exclusion of certain parts of your body
like so that's called exclusions so your
health will definitely affect your
ability to get uh coverage with no
exclusions and nothing is loading so
just now i was talking about offering a
standard term so standard turns is no
loading but
non-standard terms will be loading like
so loading is like you pay more premiums
than others then the worst case scenario
is decline decline means cannot buy it
or they don't even want to offer you the
insurance
yeah so
you might get shocked because uh you are
you think you're very young you think
you're very healthy and then you try to
apply and maybe you can be kind to they
cannot buy
yeah okay so how to check on you and
your family's health what do you need to
do or check on health booklet i think
i'm booker not much lah but yeah okay uh
most important you can check this uh
health hub application and website so
basically you log in if you're using
pass you can check all the like previous
hospital admissions all this discharge
summary some details will be on the
health application and also if you do
any uh health check up right uh with the
government
or with uh gamma-affiliated clinics
right they can also actually be uh
updated in this health hub okay
then uh if your own self got kid or your
health reports all these this is your
health reports
okay then uh if you basically do any
genetic testing uh for breast cancer
huntington disease all these can
actually affect your insurability okay
lastly uh can also consult your family
doctor for any history that
uh you you and your family might have
oh lastly is to open up your mouth and
ask your parents because actually if you
don't declare some stuff that you
already have and it's actually in some
record somewhere when you try to get a
claims
this will come and bug you in the air so
yeah
very important to declare fully of what
you already have and is everything in
the hospital records or whatever record
somewhere yeah please declare so if you
don't declare they can
uh not admit the claim you can avoid the
whole insurance okay so you pay the
insurance for nothing then you won't
ever get your premiums back yeah because
it's like you made a fraudulent
application
okay next we move on to consideration on
our needs and suitability so why why do
you need to consider okay so what are
the areas of consideration so the main
areas of consideration will be the
number one thing would be medical cost
because our medical
cost is so expensive in singapore right
so yeah first thing you need to consider
is a hospital and accident okay
then next thing even though you have
kids no kids
you will also fall sick okay so for sick
is critical illness and medical cost law
so creative illness why you you still
need a critical illness on top of your
medical cost plans right it's because uh
if you're sick you have no income other
than being a hospital bill you still pay
your everyday bills right so if you're
unable to work where is this money going
to come from
noella okay so anyway uh if you don't
purchase this critical illness insurance
when you're unable uh uh unable to walk
you will eat into your own retirement
fund or savings
and then uh some staff are not fully
covered under like accident or hospital
plans but so
uh if you read the recent news there's a
like cancer that cancer drugs not
approved by moh will not be
paid out by uh integrated health shift
plan so all this will take into
consideration when buying a critical
illness plan okay
next is a work disability
so our work disability plans are not
always sold by all insurers so you need
to check which insurers offer this case
over disability is a plan that pays you
a certain amount income as long as you
are declared unfit to work for your
current job yeah so this is not like
your usual or total permanent disability
will be like something like uh even
mental illness for example a teacher
your developmental illness cannot work
with kids all this cow says work
disability okay don't need to one so
don't see how don't you lose a leg hand
or whatever
simple things like doctor doctor sign
hand
got this movement thing or whatever it's
a calculator mental illness could be any
could be a real illness or develop due
to muscle something so all this how as
work disability so as long as a doctor
declares you unfit to work is a work
disability okay so there are many types
of work disability plans like we're not
going to detail here so but this is
should be a huge area of consideration
like because you can't who is going to
support you your parents
your spouse
yeah so anyway this is really a huge
consideration
okay next is uh total permanent
disability so what disability is when
you can't do your work total permanent
disability uh refers to
when you are once a that so you lose
your eyes your hands or your legs or you
can't do the
uh six activities of daily living so of
the six activities or daily living you
can't do three or two it counts as a
total permanent disability okay so got a
few definitions of total permanent
disability okay then last uh last few
considerations is uh death
death too early they have too late or uh
already you are quite old you're
thinking about leaving something for
kids so that legacy planning so auditory
about their flaw so dev too early why do
you need it
uh i mean you only need if you have
defenders like if you don't have
dependence it's not very important okay
without planning i believe everyone
needs luck i mean whether you think you
are going to survive until retirement
it's always good to plan for it right
yeah
okay so how do you put all these things
into consideration for needs and
suitability you need to uh sit down and
think about it or you can sit down your
advisor and think about it so like for
hospital which one am i okay with so am
i really okay with a b2 or lc class what
if i'm okay with b2c household okay i
continue with my meditation life
actually no i wouldn't recommend
continuing with medishield life because
uh malaysian life does not cover pre and
post uh hospitalization so even so if
you are okay with b2c class what just
get the basic uh integrated health shift
plan which is really very affordable i
think less than
less than one k a year
yeah you you can get it with the rider
and uh
the main plan so it's very very cheap
for those complaints these cover pre and
post pre and post can break up a lot of
course i tell you yeah okay so uh second
consideration if you're a foreigner uh
which currency to be insured in so for
example i'm a malaysian do i want to be
insured in
malaysia ringgit if i'm working in
singapore so let's say uh one day
one day uh 10 years down the road i'm
really sick already but i only buy my
insurance in malaysia and now the sink
dollar is one to four how am i going to
be enough i mean it's not going to be
enough to protect me right
so you definitely want to be insured in
your currency that you will be using to
pay for all your bills like so currency
to be insured in
okay so uh just now i mentioned about ci
so ci how much you should be protected
for so
uh if you
have read my other uh watch my other
videos you will know that uh there's two
kinds of cipl one is a
recurring one is a single payout so
singapore means uh once they pay then
that's the end of planner recurring is
uh i pay for this uh cancer that people
have they got people many different ci
that's called curry okay so how much we
insured for is like um
three years if it's recurring should be
enough three years of annual income
whereas if it's just a single payout i
would think you minimum need uh five
years of annoying
so also ci is also split into many
different kinds
uh i believe you have early ci and major
cia so
uh if you only get the major ci it means
you have to progress to the late stage
where you're already going to pass then
you get money uh to me that's not very
meaningful so
always get alicia if you can
okay
then
we move on to early death and tpd so if
that happens too early or total
permanent disability happens too early
you should recover up to 10 years of
your annual income
okay and then you need to think about
our
extent of and length of coverage so uh
for example you already married with
kids and then you want to cover until
your kids are fully grown up so usually
65 or 75 is enough
but if you want to always
uh be insured even after 75 then you
need to think about uh paying more
premiums like because it's going to
be more expensive okay and uh extent of
coverage excellent coverage usually
applies to
uh critical earners so
like there are many critical illness
plans in the market but it's like uh
there are many different conditions that
is stated in the individual plans like
so for example
i will not list the name of the plans
but it's like plan a versus plan b it
can be this one is covering a 50
condition this one cover 100 condition
so definitely the premium is going to be
different right because the external
coverage is different
yeah
okay then the next area of consideration
is product types so product types there
are many three kinds like term life
investment link product okay so
uh i think i did a video explaining
these three differences but i'll just
give you a brief overview on these three
different methods so basically term is a
pair as you use like so if you don't use
it you will net you never get anything
back okay ps use
life is uh
usually cover unto her i mean term can
also cover under 100 years old so
uh
life is uh the difference is actually in
the cash value right so let's say
uh i i actually buy life plan but 80
years why i decided i don't want to be
covered and why i want to take some
money i don't take all the money out of
my plan so i can take money back whereas
in tom plan uh if i cover in your hurry
so i take any money out of the plane at
80 years old i'll get nothing back the
plan will just be terminated okay
so both both can dominate just that this
has no cash value this has cash value
okay
then uh investment in product basically
does what it says it is like
my premiums go into investments and
premiums uh i mean improvements go into
investments then uh
the insurance charges right is deducted
from your
investments okay investment product
okay next area of consideration is uh
what people don't usually tell you like
it's a insurer reputation and premium
amount because uh israel reputation is
definitely important in the sense that
if you go for the cheapest premium right
can you be assured that you actually get
the payout
like like okay just one example like
travel insurance
they are definitely bad and good
insurers right
you if you go always go for the cheapest
one right you might not right now get uh
the full coverage that you need
yeah
okay so
is there really a difference between
different insurers well the short answer
is most likely okay premiums defer
across insurance and product type due to
the various things like so contract
definitions or coverage so like i
mentioned just now the number of ci co
uh considered and what is the additional
coverage that they afford you all these
are wordings policy contract
uh
yeah so all this makes a huge difference
okay another one is the underwriting
process why is underwriting process
important because uh
let's say like company a company a is
very stringent in the underwriting
process
so they always accept only like good
uh good
insured means uh people who apply by
those people who are like bad x right
they just don't accept them or they do a
lot of exclusions so they do not need to
pay out a lot of things so these are
strict insurers and then like people
usually don't really like them because
they say oh it's so sweet everything
also cannot yeah so this is the street
underwriting process but the thing is
with this street underwriting process
they will pay out less claims that's
because
uh if they pay out a lot of claims right
and the premium pool is unable to
support the claims right they have to
raise premiums so let's say they tell
you now right the premiums is 1 000. a
few years down the road they realize
this premium pool cannot support right
they're gonna increase the premium
so
under privating process it's a huge
uh thing in insurer
in different insurers so let's say uh
insurer b is like iii everyone also
accept but i just ask you a few
questions you you can be accepted yeah
yeah yeah i can't remember my plan so
this kind of thing right you definitely
need to uh shitty premium pool and then
next time they need to increase premiums
i believe you heard of insurance
increasing premiums halfway even though
they tell you this payment is like
guaranteed or whatever but nope they
they will still increase you if they
need to
so
don't only go for the cheapest premiums
i need to see other intangibles okay and
uh
you need a way to contract whether the
premium prices is guaranteed or not
guaranteed okay so if it is not
guaranteed they can definitely increase
it that's like integrated household plan
right
they can increase it every year the
premium if they want to
because it's not not guaranteed
okay
then what is the main difference if
you're buying like a life plan right
or endowment plan right power fund
performance is actually very important
okay
so uh let's see even if like the premium
pool is like not doing well that means
like a lot of people make claims but
actually the performance performance is
uh how the insurers actually invest the
premiums that you put to them so if they
invest the premium very well right
remember even though it's like payout a
lot of claims right still will be able
to support the
uh
the lousy claims thing so
so the python performance is actually
very important in seeing
if your premium prices can stay as it is
okay
and uh other things like how narrowly
they work the
contract and then uh whether
they
pay out the claims as per
what they say they will pay a lot
because uh i mean we all experience our
fair share of uh
buying an insurance and unable to claim
right so yeah there are some issues that
are more likes than others when it comes
to claims but there are some that are
really very strict if i say 90 days
waiting period is 90 days waiting period
i don't care you are diagnosed on day 88
or day like 89 too bad you are not under
this too bad i just care about the
contract okay
whereas there are some insurers that due
to goodwill even they are diagnosed on
like day 89 right they can actually uh
pay out the claim
another area of claims experience is how
long they take to pay out the claim and
how do you actually file for the claim
and how fast is the claim actually paid
up into your bank account so
most insurers have gradually moved to
pay now if i'm not wrong so
yeah so you will see like how many days
for example today i follow the claim
where i get my money but then i'm weak
so uh i believe for most insurers is yes
yeah but also like when they are doing
the claims right whether they will
investigate super long then even
investing it super long means a bit like
unwilling to pay out the claim so it
might be able to find reasons not to pay
the claim
so yeah so different companies have
different claims uh
payout process okay so all these are
very important then uh please remember
to pay your premiums in a yearly mode if
you want to save money because uh
if you pay on the monthly payment method
right it's actually if you add up time
shelf it will be more expensive cost
time value of money so if you have the
money you can uh pay in your yearly
premiums mode okay but uh for some plans
not sure whether all insurance charges
for like investment link plans is
actually uh same same for yearly or
money payment method
another reason to pay yearly instead of
money is because a monthly method is a
very easy for the plant to lapse and you
don't even know that the plant labs
because uh it's like monthly deduction
from your bank account or money
deduction credit card then what happens
when your credit card expires then a lot
of people think they still have the plan
but actually the plan no more enforce
yeah so
always go for yearly premiums and yearly
premiums they want them usually send you
a letter to pay your premiums okay
so
another difference is the application
process experience so let's say i want
to buy direct because i i think it's
cheaper
then uh because everything i applied
online i had to read everything myself
because nobody is servicing me i need to
do everything myself
so
there is a lot of difference like the
application process i want to ask hey is
this covered oh is this uh when can i
claim this
what so all these questions nobody's
gonna answer you you need to go and
type email and send in one by one yeah
so application process experience is
very different
yep and then after sales experience so
let's say you buy from
i don't know like uh those kind of not
so famous insurers after sales
experience is going to be this smaller
tell you
yeah okay then uh
other things like small things like
whether they have a mobile application
for you to take a look at your your uh
insurance sync pass log in for easy
assess overview license is really one
that means you can go in right yeah but
not every insurer offered it so all
these things are all after sales
experience
okay
okay lastly uh it boils down to
servicing agent okay so what are the
qualities that matter in servicing agent
okay so i think one is uh need to be
honest and trusted okay so recommend you
based on your needs and your suitability
rather than other things
okay
then next is uh closeness la closer is
actually quite quite high on the list
because it's like uh if you're not
willing to share much with
the servicing agent right it's very hard
to actually recommend
suitable solutions
okay and also claims wise right if you
communicate more it will be more
efficient so let's say
uh
i bought an accident plan from person a
then person a don't know i fall down
they cannot tell me oh you fall down you
can claim you know so it's like uh
closeness will definitely increase your
your efficiency of your claims like for
example uh i'm following my clients on
social media i see them uh why
hospitalized why food poisoning oh you
know footballing can claim or not so all
these things closeness really matters
okay so let's say you buy from the
direct you buy from the website and you
want to get a quote yourself nobody's
gonna tell you this song can claim what
you forget too bad lah yeah so that's
the thing
okay and i think it's a knowledge and
education background so
i believe you have met your fair share
of advisors who don't know what the hell
they are talking about
yeah so knowledge and education
background is actually very important to
advise on product suitability and other
areas such as a tax investment or life
yeah i mean you don't put your life into
someone's hands without knowing this
personal education background so let's
say yeah let's see
does this advisor who go around
i i mean maybe he's in his first year of
career he didn't even do super well then
he said go and buy a car and then i tell
you his savings is less than thank you
you want to put your your life into
hands of someone like that
yeah so actually very important have a
good knowledge good education background
okay
so he can't even like manage his own
life and you want to manage your your
financial life oh my god this is quite
scary right
yeah okay and i think it's a
dependability uh when you encounter an
emergency and you want to reach your
advisor or journey
for advice
uh
whether you are able to do it like so
dependability and then uh if you want to
find out how to get dependable one uh
definitely go for referrals because they
have experience with
their current advisors usually the good
ones are the one who cares about health
shield her health she is the lowest
uh lowest commission those commission
but the most claims
then uh if the advisor don't really care
about this person who only buy hell
right yeah obviously it's like only out
there for commissions but
yeah
okay
lastly is uh how long this advisor will
stay like so if the current so let's say
i'm your agent then one day i leave
right then the new one that's servicing
you right won't be receiving these
commissions from you they are less
likely to be willing to serve you well
so there's human nature like i never
received anything from you like why
should i serve you well
yeah but it's i mean it depends on
individual agents but that will be the
normal micellar
yeah
okay i've come to the end of today's
session
okay so hope you guys have learned
something new today and then uh yeah
please share this video with your
friends and families if you think this
video has helped you and if you have any
questions
don't leave me a comment just message me
or reach me on other social media
because if you leave a comment i have to
reply publicly and not everything can be
replied publicly yeah okay so that's the
end of today's video thank you everyone
bye oh please help too like and
subscribe bye
[Music]
so
[Applause]
[Music]
you